[Music]
have you ever tried wrapping your mind
around o off2 but ended up lost in the
sea of jargons that's why we're here
today we're breaking down these complex
Concepts into digestible explanations
let's Dive Right In imagine the early
days of the internet sharing info was
straightforward just hand over your
username and password to another service
and they could access anything they
wanted this practice is fry upon these
days but we might still encounter this
practice in certain personal finance
software to scrape information from
crusto Banks luckily we have something
much better these days enter OA 2 OA 2
is like giving someone a special key
this key allows them to access specific
information in another application we
control who gets access to our data
without having to share a password and
yes we can revoke that key at any time
now let's play this out with an example
consider a photo storage application
Snap Store we've been using it to store
our photos and now we want to print some
of them using a thirdparty printing
service PR magic instead of manually
uploading each photo to PR magic we ask
PR magic to do the job with a simple
click we Grant PR magic permission to
access our photos on Snap Store using o
Off 2 preager can then access our Snap
Store photos on our behalf without ever
knowing our Snap Store login
credentials this is an example of the O
off flow is an elegant stance between us
Prem magic and snap store all
orchestrated by o of2 now let's unpack
this further in this context we are the
resource owner because we own our photos
on Snap Store Snap Store is the resource
server that stores our photos pre magic
is the client that wants to access the
photos the authorization server could be
a part of snap store or an external
identity provider and is responsible for
handling the O off2 process let's follow
the oof2 flow in this scenario it begins
when we instruct pre magic to fetch
photos from Snap Store pre magic sends a
client ID and scope
which represent the access level
requested to snap store's authorization
server as a resource owner we
authenticate directly with SNAP store
and Grant Prem magic the consent to
access our photos once consent is
granted the authorization server sends
an authorization code back to PR magic
Prim magic then presents this
authorization code is client ID and
client secret to the authorization
server now the client secret is a
private key shared only between PR magic
and the authorization
server if the authorization server
verifies the authorization code client
ID and client secret IT issues an access
token to PR
magic finally Prim magic uses this
access token to request our photos from
snap store's resource server this all
off to process ensures that our Snap
Store login credentials are never
exposed to pre magic while allowing pre
magic to access only the photos we
authorized it to see it's also important
to note that the access token can be set
to expire after a certain time or can be
revoked by us at any point providing an
additional layer of
security oa2 also support refresh tokens
which can be used to obtain a new access
token when the o one expires without
requiring our in ition that's o off to
in a nutshell is an essential piece of
the web security infrastructure and the
backbone of many secure Seamless app
interactions we use
daily if you like our videos you may
like our system design newsletter as
well it covers topics and Trends in
large scale system design trusted by
400,000 readers subscribe that blog.
byby go.com